# BUU TRUONG PHAN

truongbuu.github.io - truongbuu94@gmail.com - Google Scholar - LinkedIn

About me: I am a researcher in deep learning and computer vision, specialized in 3D object detection, uncertainty and adversarial robustness. Other interested research topics include: graph-based learning, matrix methods, information theory, optimization and probability.

Main toolkits and libraries: Python, Tensorflow, Pytorch, scikit-learn, C/C++, Git/Github, OpenCV, Docker.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

#### LG Electronics AI Lab

May 2021 - Now

AI Research Engineer

Canada

- · Developed a novel and occlusion-aware neural architecture for human pose estimation.
- · Fast-prototype multiple AI solutions and export deep learning models for production.
- · Research on out-of-distribution detection and graph-based learning.

**Algolux** Oct 2019 - May 2021

Research Scientist - Deep Learning and Computer Vision

Canada

- · My role is to research and implement computer vision technologies for self-driving cars (3D stereo object detection, segmentation, tracking, etc.)
- Formulated and developed a new optimization algorithm for black-box adversarial attack that targets a specific ISP module.
- · Proposed and developed a neural network model for the hidden objects tracking problem using radar (nonline-of-sight imaging). Project Link.
- · Developed and benchmarked different object detection architectures.
- · Developed active learning algorithms for object detection.

#### Waterloo Intelligent Systems Engineering Lab, University of Waterloo Sep 2017 - Sep 2019 Graduate Research Assistant

- · Researched in the area of Bayesian deep learning, image segmentation, active learning and anomaly detection. My thesis studies different aspects of Bayesian deep learning model in the context of road-scene image segmentation. Thesis Link.
- · Formulated and developed a distillation technique for Bayesian neural networks.
- · Developed a camera obstruction detection model and integrated it from Tensorflow to C++.
- · Developed functionalities for the Autonomoose self-driving car platform (Project Autonomoose).

# BlueSeed Digital Data Scientist Intern

Dec 2016 - Jul 2017

Vietnam

· I developed machine learning models for market segmentation and topic modelling. I also integrated the model into production using Spark technologies.

# **EDUCATION**

## University of Waterloo

Sep 2017 - Sep 2019

Master of Applied Science, Advisor: Prof. Krzysztof Czarnecki

International University - Vietnam National University

Overall GPA: 93.17/100

Specialization: Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence

Sep 2012 - Sep 2016 Overall GPA: 91.5/100

B.Eng in Electrical Engineering (summa cum laude)

# **PUBLICATIONS**

1. Buu Phan, Fahim Mannan and Felix Heide. "Adversarial Imaging Pipelines." CVPR, 2021.

- 2. Nicolas Scheiner, Florian Kraus, Fangyin Wei, Buu Phan, Fahim Mannan, Nils Appenrodt, Werner Ritter et al. "Seeing Around Street Corners: Non-Line-of-Sight Detection and Tracking In-the-Wild Using Doppler Radar." In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, pp. 2068-2077. 2020. https://www.cs.princeton.edu/~fheide/DopplerNLOS/.
- 3. Buu Phan, Samin Khan, Rick Salay, and Krzysztof Czarnecki. "Bayesian uncertainty quantification with synthetic data." In International Conference on Computer Safety, Reliability, and Security, pp. 378-390. Springer, Cham, 2019. Best paper award at the Second International Workshop on Artificial Intelligence Safety Engineering.

- Samin Khan, Buu Phan, Rick Salay, and Krzysztof Czarnecki. "ProcSy: Procedural Synthetic Dataset Generation Towards Influence Factor Studies Of Semantic Segmentation Networks." In CVPR Workshops, pp. 88-96. 2019.
- Sachin Vernekar, Ashish Gaurav, Taylor Denouden, Buu Phan, Vahdat Abdelzad, Rick Salay, and Krzysztof Czarnecki. "Analysis of confident-classifiers for out-of-distribution detection." ICLR SafeML Workshop 2019.
- Buu Phan, Rick Salay, Krzysztof Czarnecki, Vahdat Abdelzad, Taylor Denouden, Sachin Vernekar, "Calibrating Uncertainties in Object Localization Task", NeurIPS Bayesian Deep Learning Workshop, 2018.
- Ian Colwell, Buu Phan, Shahwar Saleem, Rick Salay, and Krzysztof Czarnecki. "An automated vehicle safety concept based on runtime restriction of the operational design domain." In 2018 IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV), pp. 1910-1917. IEEE, 2018.

# **PREPRINTS**

- 1. Abdelzad, Vahdat, Krzysztof Czarnecki, Rick Salay, Taylor Denounden, Sachin Vernekar, and **Buu Phan**. "Detecting Out-of-Distribution Inputs in Deep Neural Networks Using an Early-Layer Output." arXiv preprint arXiv:1910.10307 (2019).
- 2. Denouden Taylor, Rick Salay, Krzysztof Czarnecki, Vahdat Abdelzad, **Buu Phan**, and Sachin Vernekar. "Improving reconstruction autoencoder out-of-distribution detection with mahalanobis distance." arXiv preprint arXiv:1812.02765 (2018).

## AWARDS, SCHOLARSHIPS & ACHIEVEMENTS

• Best paper award, Workshop on Artificial Intelligence Safety Engineering	2019
• Toyota Canada Graduate Scholarship	2018-2019
• NSERC CREATE, Student Grant	2018-2019
• Faculty of Engineering Awards for top graduate students, University of Waterloo	2018, 2019
• International Master's Student Awards, University of Waterloo	2017-2019
• Graduate Research Studentship, University of Waterloo	2017
• Honor Student Award, Vietnam National University	2016
• Valedictorian, International University	2016